Rae Rohfeld Papers
Rae Rohfeld Papers
1988-1993
Rohfeld, Rae Wahl
0.75 linear ft.
Papers of the adult education professor at Syracuse University. Collection includes correspondence, conference material, writings. Most relates to several working conferences on the history of adult education held at SU.
2537526
Biographical History
Rae Rohfeld was a professor of adult education at Syracuse University and later taught at Empire State College. As a member of the Syracuse University Kellogg Project, she coordinated several conferences on the history of adult education. The first was a traditional conference but subsequent ones were structured as "working conferences, " meaning that time was built into the conferences for scholars to actually carry out research among collection materials, present preliminary findings, and receive interactive feedback from fellow conference participants.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Rae Rohfeld Papers is divided into two series. Conferences and meetings contains material from several annual conferences on the history of adult education held at Syracuse University under the auspices of the Kellogg Project; the 1988 International Conference on Adult Education held in Aachen, Germany, at which Rohfeld represented the Kellogg Project; and the History of Education Society's 1991 meeting. This includes conference proceedings, agenda, correspondence, notes, and other material. Writings contains several papers written by Rohfeld.
Arrangement of the Collection
Conference and meeting material is in alphabetical order by conference title and within that in chronological order. Writing is in alphabetical order by title.
Related Material
has more than 50 collections relating to adult education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Rohfeld, Rae Wahl.; Syracuse University Kellogg Project.; Adult education -- United States.; Adult education -- Research.; Adult education teachers -- Training of.; History of Education Society.; International Conference on Adult Education.; Articles.; Papers (document genres); Proceedings.; Adult education educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Rae Rohfeld, 2007
Inventory
- Conferences and meetings
  - History of Adult Education
    - 1989 conference, includes printed and bound proceedings; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1990 conference (Box 1)
    - 1991 conference (Box 1)
    - 1993 conference (Box 1)
  - History of Education Society
    - 1991 annual meeting (Box 2)
  - International Conference on Adult Education
    - 1988 conference (Box 2)
- Writings
  - The challenge of documenting adult education, 1991; paper presented at History of Education Society meeting (Box 2)
  - Collaboration between voluntary organizations and the state for adult education in the United States, 1988; paper presented at International Conference on Adult Education (Box 2)
  - Reconstructing the mainstream: issues in history of race, class and gender, 1991; paper presented at Commission of Professors of Adult Education (CPAE) meeting (Box 2)
  - The working conference: A vehicle for historical research, 1992 (Box 2)